<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.1/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="../../../../../../formatter/com.compart.documentation.formatter/resources/schematron/cpdocbook.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<!DOCTYPE book [
<!ENTITY % compartentities SYSTEM "../../../../../../formatter/com.compart.documentation.formatter/resources/entities/entities.ent">
%compartentities;
]>
<sect2 xml:id="db_pil_wui_filterSettings" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.1" xml:lang="en-US">
    <title>Configuring Filter Settings</title>
    <para>Some views of the <productname>&dbpi;</productname> web interface provide the option to configure filter settings to reduce the number of items displayed in the overview table. You can define one or more filters for each view. To do this, click the <guilabel>Filter</guilabel> button in the desired view to display the available filters for the columns of the overview table. In the respective views, most table columns are also available as filters. The filter functionality is available in the following views.</para>
    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>Application activities</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
                <para>For more information, see <xref
                        linkend="application_activities_filters"/>.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>Process activities</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
                <para>For more information, see <xref linkend="process_activities_filters"
                    />.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>Job activities</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
                <para>For more information, see <xref linkend="job_activities_filters"
                    />.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>Scheduler activities</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
                <para>For more information, see <xref linkend="scheduler_activities_filters"
                    />.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>Jobs</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
                <para>For more information, see <xref linkend="jobs_filters"/>.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>Documents</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
                <para>For more information, see <xref linkend="documents_filters"/>.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>Mail Pieces</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
                <para>For more information, see <xref linkend="mailPieces_filters"/>.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>Mail piece trackings</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
                <para>For more information, see <xref linkend="mailPieceTrackings_filters"
                    />.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>Workflow templates</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
                <para>For more information, see <xref linkend="workflowTemplates_filters"
                    />.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>Workflow instances</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
                <para>For more information, see <xref linkend="workflowInstances_filters"
                    />.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term><guilabel>Workflow activities</guilabel></term>
            <listitem>
                <para>For more information, see <xref linkend="workflowActivities_filters"
                    />.</para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <para>The following sections contain an overview of the available filters with the available settings for each view that supports filtering.</para>
    <note>
        <para>Please note that the string comparison for all filters used by <productname>&dbpw;</productname> is not case-sensitive. For example, if you enter <userinput>IMPORT</userinput> as filter text, scheduler activities with the name <guilabel>import</guilabel> will also be found.</para>
    </note>
    <sect3 xml:id="application_activities_filters">
        <title>Filters for Application Activities</title>
        <para>The following list contains the available filter settings for the <guilabel>Application Activities</guilabel> view.</para>
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>ID</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available application activities based on the specified string. You can specify a complete ID or part of an ID. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose ID exactly matches the specified ID or whose ID contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Type</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can select a type from the full list of available types of application activities.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please keep in mind that the dropdown list does not support multi-selection.</para>
                    </note>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>State</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can select a state from the full list of available states.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please keep in mind that the dropdown list does not support multi-selection.</para>
                    </note>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Created</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The <guilabel>Created</guilabel> filter consists of two calendar elements. In both calendar elements you can select a date and, if required, a time. If you select a date/time only in the first calendar, only entries created since the selected date/time will be displayed in the overview table. If you select a date/time only in the second calendar, only entries created up to the selected date/time will be displayed in the overview table.</para>
                    <para>Alternatively, you can define a time period by selecting a start date and an end date (and time) from the two calendars. If you define a time period, only entries (application activities) created after the specified start date (/time) and before the specified end date (/time) will be displayed in the overview table.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </sect3>
    <sect3 xml:id="process_activities_filters">
        <title>Filters for Process Activities</title>
        <para>The following list contains the available filter settings for the <guilabel>Process Activities</guilabel> view.</para>
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>ID</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available process activities based on the specified string. You can specify a complete ID or part of an ID. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose ID exactly matches the specified ID or whose ID contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Process</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can select a process from the full list of configured processes.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please keep in mind that the dropdown list does not support multi-selection.</para>
                    </note>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Sequence</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available process activities based on the specified string. You can specify a complete sequence name or part of a sequence name. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose sequence exactly matches the specified sequence name or whose sequence  contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>handler</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available process activities based on the specified string. You can specify a complete handler name or part of a handler name The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose handler exactly matches the specified handler name or whose handler  contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Job</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available process activities based on the specified string. To do this, you need to specify a complete job ID. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose job ID exactly matches the specified ID or whose job ID contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>State</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can select a state from the full list of available states.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please keep in mind that the dropdown list does not support multi-selection.</para>
                    </note>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Job</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available process activities based on the specified string. To do this, you need to specify a complete selector value. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose selector exactly matches the specified selector value.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </sect3>
    <sect3 xml:id="job_activities_filters">
        <title>Filters for Job Activities</title>
        <para>The following list contains the available filter settings for the <guilabel>Job Activities</guilabel> view.</para>
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>ID</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available job activities based on the specified string. You can specify a complete ID or part of an ID. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose ID exactly matches the specified ID or whose ID contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Process</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can select a process from the full list of configured processes.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please keep in mind that the dropdown list does not support multi-selection.</para>
                    </note>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Source Job</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available job activities based on the specified string. To do this, you need to specify a complete job ID. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose job ID exactly matches the specified ID or whose job ID contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Job</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available process activities based on the specified string. To do this, you need to specify a complete job ID. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose job ID exactly matches the specified ID or whose job ID contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Action</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available process activities based on the specified string. You can specify the full action name or part of an action name. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose action name  exactly matches the specified action name or whose action name  contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Created</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The <guilabel>Created</guilabel> filter consists of two calendar elements. In both calendar elements you can select a date and, if required, a time. If you select a date/time only in the first calendar, only entries created since the selected date/time will be displayed in the overview table. If you select a date/time only in the second calendar, only entries created up to the selected date/time will be displayed in the overview table.</para>
                    <para>Alternatively, you can define a time period by selecting a start date and an end date (and time) from the two calendars. If you define a time period, only entries (application activities) created after the specified start date (/time) and before the specified end date (/time) will be displayed in the overview table.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Context</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available job activities based on the specified string. You can specify a complete context ID or part of a context ID. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose context ID exactly matches the specified context ID or whose context ID contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </sect3>
    <sect3 xml:id="scheduler_activities_filters">
        <title>Filters for Scheduler Activities</title>
        <para>The following list contains the available filter settings for the <guilabel>Scheduler  Activities</guilabel> view.</para>
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Group</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available scheduler activities based on the specified string. You can specify the full group name or part of a group name. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose name exactly matches the specified group name or whose group name contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Name</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available scheduler activities based on the specified string. You can specify the full name of a scheduler activity or part of the name of a scheduler activity. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose name exactly matches the specified name or whose name contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>State</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can select a state from the full list of available states.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please keep in mind that the dropdown list does not support multi-selection.</para>
                    </note>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Type</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can select a type from the total list of available types of scheduler activities.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please keep in mind that the dropdown list does not support multi-selection.</para>
                    </note>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Task</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available scheduler activities based on the specified string. You can specify the full title of a task (e.g.&nbsp; <userinput>import#GlobalInserts</userinput>) or part of a task title. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose task title exactly matches the specified title or whose task title contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Created</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The <guilabel>Created</guilabel> filter consists of two calendar elements. In both calendar elements you can select a date and, if required, a time. If you select a date/time only in the first calendar, only entries created since the selected date/time will be displayed in the overview table. If you select a date/time only in the second calendar, only entries created up to the selected date/time will be displayed in the overview table.</para>
                    <para>Alternatively, you can define a time period by selecting a start date and an end date (and time) from the two calendars. If you define a time period, only entries (scheduler activities) created after the specified start date (or time) and before the specified end date (or time) will be displayed in the overview table.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </sect3>
    <sect3 xml:id="jobs_filters">
        <title>Filters for Jobs</title>
        <para>The following list contains the available filter settings for the <guilabel>Jobs</guilabel> view.</para>
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>ID</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available jobs based on the specified string. You can specify a complete ID or part of an ID. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose ID exactly matches the specified ID or whose ID contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Class</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can select a class from the full list of available job classes.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please keep in mind that the dropdown list does not support multi-selection.</para>
                    </note>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Pages</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available jobs based on a specified integer value. Specify a total number of pages in the job to display only jobs whose total number of pages is equal to the specified number.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Sheets</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available jobs based on a specified integer value. Specify a total number of sheets in the job to display only jobs whose total number of sheets is equal to the specified number.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Documents</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available jobs based on a specified integer value. Specify a total number of documents in the job to display only jobs whose total number of documents is equal to the specified number.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Created</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The <guilabel>Created</guilabel> filter consists of two calendar elements. In both calendar elements you can select a date and, if required, a time. If you select a date/time only in the first calendar, only entries created since the selected date/time will be displayed in the overview table. If you select a date/time only in the second calendar, only entries created up to the selected date/time will be displayed in the overview table.</para>
                    <para>Alternatively, you can define a time period by selecting a start date and an end date (and time) from the two calendars. If you define a time period, only entries (jobs) created after the specified start date (or time) and before the specified end date (or time) will be displayed in the overview table.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para>In addition, you can change filter settings for jobs in the <guilabel>Settings</guilabel> dialog (for more information, see <xref linkend="set_jobFilter_mode"
                            />).</para>
                    </note>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </sect3>
    <sect3 xml:id="documents_filters">
        <title>Filters for Documents</title>
        <note>
            <para>Please keep in mind that filtering and sorting are not supported for global documents. You can filter and/or sort only job-specific documents.</para>
        </note>
        <para>The following list contains the available filter settings for the <guilabel>Documennts</guilabel> view.</para>
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>ID</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available documents based on the specified string. You can specify a complete ID or part of an ID. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose ID exactly matches the specified ID or whose ID contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Type</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can select a type from the full list of available document types.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please keep in mind that the dropdown list does not support multi-selection.</para>
                    </note>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Class</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can select a class from the full list of available document classes.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please keep in mind that the dropdown list does not support multi-selection.</para>
                    </note>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Created</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The <guilabel>Created</guilabel> filter consists of two calendar elements. In both calendar elements you can select a date and, if required, a time. If you select a date/time only in the first calendar, only entries created since the selected date/time will be displayed in the overview table. If you select a date/time only in the second calendar, only entries created up to the selected date/time will be displayed in the overview table.</para>
                    <para>Alternatively, you can define a time period by selecting a start date and an end date (and time) from the two calendars. If you define a time period, only entries (documents) created after the specified start date (or time) and before the specified end date (or time) will be displayed in the overview table.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>State</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available documents based on the specified string. You can specify a complete status or part of a status designation. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose status exactly matches the specified status designation or whose status contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Usage</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available documents based on the specified string. You can specify a usage or a part of a usage designation. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose usage exactly matches the specified usage designation or whose usage contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Priority</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available documents based on the specified string. You can specify a complete priority or a part of a priority designation. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose priority exactly matches the specified priority designation or whose priority contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </sect3>
    <sect3 xml:id="mailPieces_filters">
        <title>Filters for Mail Pieces</title>
        <para>The following list contains the available filter settings for the <guilabel>Mail Pieces</guilabel> view.</para>
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>ID</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available mail pieces based on the specified string. You can specify a complete ID or part of an ID. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose ID exactly matches the specified ID or whose ID contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Envelope</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available mail pieces based on the specified string. You can specify a complete envelope designation or a part of an envelope designation. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose envelope name designation matches the specified envelope designation or whose envelope designation contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Sequence</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available mail pieces based on the specified string. You can specify a complete sequence designation or a part of a sequence designation. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose sequence designation exactly matches the specified sequence designation or whose sequence designation contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Weight</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available mail pieces based on a specified integer value. Specify the desired weight to display only mail pieces whose weight corresponds to the specified weight.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Sheets</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available mail pieces based on a specified integer value. Specify a total number of sheets in the mail piece to display only mail pieces  whose total number of sheets is equal to the specified number.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </sect3>
    <sect3 xml:id="mailPieceTrackings_filters">
        <title>Filters for Mail Piece Trackings</title>
        <para>The following list contains the available filter settings for the <guilabel>Mail Piece Trackings</guilabel> view.</para>
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>ID</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available mail piece trackings based on the specified string. You can specify a complete ID or part of an ID. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose ID exactly matches the specified ID or whose ID contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Mail Piece ID</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available mail piece trackings based on the specified string. You can specify a complete mail piece ID or part of a mail piece ID. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose mail piece ID exactly matches the specified ID or whose mail piece ID contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Sequence ID</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available mail piece trackings based on the specified string. You can specify a complete sequence ID or part of a sequence ID. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose sequence ID exactly matches the specified ID or whose sequence ID contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Information</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available mail piece trackings based on the specified string. The existing entries will be automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose information exactly matches the specified information or whose information contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </sect3>
    <sect3 xml:id="workflowTemplates_filters">
        <title>Filters for Workflow Templates</title>
        <para>The following list contains the available filter settings for the <guilabel>Workflow Templates</guilabel> view.</para>
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>ID</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available workflow templates based on the specified string. You can specify a complete ID or part of an ID. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose ID exactly matches the specified ID or whose ID contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Process</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can select a process from the full list of configured processes.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please keep in mind that the dropdown list does not support multi-selection.</para>
                    </note>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Name</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available workflow templates based on the specified string. You can specify the full template name or part of a template name. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose template name exactly matches the specified name or whose template name contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Automatic</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can select the desired value (<guilabel>true</guilabel> or <guilabel>false</guilabel>) from the dropdown list of available values.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please keep in mind that the dropdown list does not support multi-selection.</para>
                    </note>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Priority</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available workflow templates based on the specified string. You must specify a complete value. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose priority exactly matches the specified value.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Description</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available workflow templates based on the specified string. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose description exactly matches the specified text or whose description contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </sect3>
    <sect3 xml:id="workflowInstances_filters">
        <title>Filters for Workflow Instances</title>
        <para>The following list contains the available filter settings for the <guilabel>Workflow Instances</guilabel> view.</para>
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>ID</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available workflow instances based on the specified string. You can specify a complete ID or part of an ID. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose ID exactly matches the specified ID or whose ID contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Process</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can select a process from the full list of configured processes.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please keep in mind that the dropdown list does not support multi-selection.</para>
                    </note>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>State</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can select the desired processing status of the workflow instances to be displayed from the overall list of available workflow statuses.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please keep in mind that the dropdown list does not support multi-selection.</para>
                    </note>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Last action</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available workflow instances based on the specified string. To do this, you need to specify a complete numerical value. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose numerical value (for example <userinput>1</userinput> or <userinput>3</userinput>) exactly matches the specified value.</para>

                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Template</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available workflow instances based on the specified string. To do this, you need to specify a complete numerical value to specify the template based on which the instance was created. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose template number (for example <userinput>2</userinput>) exactly matches the specified value.</para>

                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Jobs</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available workflow instances based on the specified string. You must specify a complete value. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose job ID exactly matches the specified ID or whose job ID contains the specified string</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </sect3>
    <sect3 xml:id="workflowActivities_filters">
        <title>Filters for Workflow Activities</title>
        <para>The following list contains the available filter settings for the <guilabel>Workflow Activities</guilabel> view.</para>
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>ID</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available workflow activities based on the specified string. You can specify a complete ID or part of an ID. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose ID exactly matches the specified ID or whose ID contains the specified string.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Process</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can select a process from the full list of configured processes.</para>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please keep in mind that the dropdown list does not support multi-selection.</para>
                    </note>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>State</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can select the desired processing status of the workflow activities to be displayed from the overall list of available workflow states.</para>
                    <para>The following values are currently available:</para>
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><guilabel>CREATED</guilabel></para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><guilabel>PAUSED</guilabel></para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><guilabel>EXECUTING</guilabel></para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><guilabel>FINISHED</guilabel></para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><guilabel>INTERRUPTED</guilabel></para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><guilabel>FAILED</guilabel></para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please keep in mind that the dropdown list does not support multi-selection.</para>
                    </note>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Instance</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available workflow activities based on the specified string. You need to specify a numerical value (which is treated as a string). The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose instance value (for example <userinput>1</userinput> or <userinput>3</userinput>) exactly matches the specified value.</para>

                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Template</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available workflow activities based on the specified string. To do this, you need specify a numeric value (which is treated as a string) to identify the template based on which the workflow instance was created. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose template number (for example <userinput>2</userinput>) exactly matches the specified value.</para>

                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Action</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available workflow activities based on the specified string. To do this, you need to specify a numerical value (which is treated as a string) to filter for a specific action. The existing entries are automatically filtered using the specified string to display only those entries whose action number (for example, <userinput>2</userinput>) exactly matches the specified value.</para>

                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Job</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>You can filter the available workflow activities based on the specified string. You must specify a complete value. The existing entries are automatically filtered based on the specified string to display only those entries whose job ID exactly matches the specified ID or whose job ID contains the specified string</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </sect3>
</sect2>