<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.1/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="../../../../../../formatter/com.compart.documentation.formatter/resources/schematron/cpdocbook.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<!DOCTYPE book [
<!ENTITY % compartentities SYSTEM "../../../../../../formatter/com.compart.documentation.formatter/resources/entities/entities.ent">
%compartentities;
]>
<chapter xml:id="db_pil_wui_workflowTemplatesView" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.1" xml:lang="en-US">
    <title>Working with Workflow Templates</title>
    <para>When working with workflows, a distinction is made between workflow templates, workflow instances and workflow activities. Workflow templates are JSON objects that specify the general structure of a workflow. Based on a workflow template, any number of (executable) workflow instances can be created. Workflow activities are linked to a specific workflow instance (for more information on workflow instances, see <xref linkend="db_pil_wui_workflowInstancesView"/>, for more information on workflow activities, see <xref
            linkend="db_pil_wui_workflowActivitiesView"/>).</para>
    <para>The following actions are supported for the <guilabel>Workflow Templates</guilabel> view:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para><xref linkend="create_workflowTemplate"/></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para><xref linkend="display_workflowTemplates"/></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para><xref linkend="display_workflowTemplateDetails"/></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para><xref linkend="filter_workflowTemplates"/></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para><xref linkend="modify_workflowTemplate"/></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para><xref linkend="multi_edit_workflowTemplates"/></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para><xref linkend="delete_workflowTemplates"/></para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <sect1 xml:id="create_workflowTemplate"><?dbhtml filename="SearchWorkflowTemplatesView.html" ?><title>Uploading a Workflow Template</title>
        <para>You can upload a predefined workflow template as a JSON file. The uploaded JSON file can contain one or more templates.</para>
        <para>Follow the steps below to upload a workflow template as a JSON file to the server and display it in the web interface.</para>
        <procedure>
            <step>
                <para>Switch to the <guilabel>Workflow Templates</guilabel> view.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>In the navigation bar of the web interface, click <inlinemediaobject><alt>Create Button</alt><imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="images/btn_add.png" align="left" format="PNG"
                                scalefit="1"/>
                        </imageobject></inlinemediaobject> (Create).</para>
                <result>
                    <para>The <guilabel>Upload Workflow Templates</guilabel> dialog opens.</para>
                </result>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>Click the <guibutton>Select File</guibutton> button next to the <guilabel>JSON File</guilabel> field.</para>
                <result>
                    <para>The File Selection dialog opens.</para>
                </result>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>In the file selection dialog, select the desired JSON file from the directory tree.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>In the file selection dialog, click <guibutton>Open</guibutton> to confirm the selection.</para>
                <result>
                    <para>The file selection dialog closes and the name of the selected file is copied to the JSON File field.</para>
                    <mediaobject><alt>Upload JSON file dialog</alt><imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="images/dia_uploadJSONWorkflowTemplate.png"
                                align="left" format="PNG" width="12cm"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </result>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>In the <guilabel>Upload Workflow Templates</guilabel> dialog, click the <guibutton>Upload</guibutton> button to upload the selected JSON file to the server.</para>
            </step>
            <result>
                <para>The workflow template defined in the JSON file is displayed (or multiple workflow templates are displayed) in the <guilabel>Workflow Templates</guilabel> view.</para>
            </result>
        </procedure>
    </sect1>
    <sect1 xml:id="display_workflowTemplates">
        <title>Listing Workflow Templates</title>
        <para>You can display an overview of the workflow templates uploaded to the server in the workspace of the <guilabel>Workflow Templates</guilabel> view.</para>
        <mediaobject><alt>Screenshot Workflow Templates view</alt><imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/scr_WorkflowTemplatesView.png" width="14cm"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        <para>The overview table displays the following information for each existing workflow template by default:</para>
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>ID</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The unique identifier  (sequential number) of the workflow template.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Process</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The user-defined name of the process with which the workflow template is connected.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Name</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The user-defined name of the workflow template.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Automatic</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The value specifies whether processing within the workflow instances (generated from the workflow template) should be automated or manually controlled. With the default value <code>true</code> individual processing steps are started automatically. With the value <code>false</code> individual steps must be started manually.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Priority</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Priority of the workflows (generated from the template) within the processing sequence.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><guilabel>Description</guilabel></term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Optional description of the workflow template to document special features and distinguishing characteristics.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </sect1>
    <sect1 xml:id="display_workflowTemplateDetails">
        <title>Displaying Workflow Template Details</title>
        <para>If you select a workflow template in the overview table, the information about the selected workflow template is displayed in the details pane. The details pane contains the same scope of information as the overview table.</para>
        <mediaobject><alt>Commands view with details pane</alt><imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/scr_WorkflowTemaplatesViewDetails.png" align="left"
                    width="15cm" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </sect1>
    <sect1 xml:id="filter_workflowTemplates">
        <title>Filtering Workflow Templates</title>
        <para>Use this action to filter the overview of available workflow templates based on the available columns.</para>
        <para>Proceed as follows to filter the existing workflow templates and thus reduce the number of displayed workflow templates.</para>
        <procedure>
            <step>
                <para>Switch to the <guilabel>Workflow Templates</guilabel> view.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>In the navigation bar of the view, click <guibutton>Filter</guibutton>.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>You can filter the existing workflow templates by ID (simple filter) or by other parameters (for more information about filter criteria, see <xref
                        linkend="db_pil_wui_filterSettings"/>).</para>
            </step>
        </procedure>
    </sect1>
    <sect1 xml:id="modify_workflowTemplate">
        <title>Modifying a Workflow Template</title>
        <para>You can edit the workflow template properties.</para>

        <para>Proceed as follows to edit the values of an existing workflow  template:</para>
        <procedure>
            <step>
                <para>Switch to the <guilabel>Workflow Templates</guilabel> view.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>Select the required entry from the overview table.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>In the navigation bar of the view, click <inlinemediaobject><alt>Button Edit</alt><imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="images/btn_edit.png" scalefit="1"/>
                        </imageobject></inlinemediaobject> (Edit).</para>
                <result>
                    <para>The entry switches to editing mode.</para>
                </result>
            </step>            
            <step>
                <para>Enter the desired new values in the individual fields or select one of the available values from the dropdown lists.</para>
            </step>            
            <step>
                <stepalternatives>
                    <step>
                        <para>Click <inlinemediaobject><alt>Save button</alt><imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="images/btn_save.png" align="left"
                                        format="PNG" scalefit="1"/>
                                </imageobject></inlinemediaobject> (Save), to save the changed workflow template and exit the editing mode.</para>
                        <result>
                            <para>The editing mode is terminated and the workflow template is displayed with the new values in the overview table.</para>
                        </result>
                    </step>
                    <step>
                        <para>Click <inlinemediaobject><alt>Cancel button</alt><imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="images/btn_cancel.png" align="left"
                                        format="PNG" scalefit="1"/>
                                </imageobject></inlinemediaobject> (Cancel), to cancel workflow template editing and exit the editing mode without saving the changes.</para>
                    </step>
                </stepalternatives>
            </step>
        </procedure>
    </sect1>
    <sect1 xml:id="multi_edit_workflowTemplates">
        <title>Editing Multiple Workflow Templates</title>
        <para>Use this action to edit selected values for multiple workflow  templates in one step.</para>
        <note>
            <para>Please keep in mind that this function defines the same values for all selected workflow templates.</para>
        </note>
        <para>Proceed as follows to edit the settings of the selected workflow templates.</para>
        <procedure>
            <step>
                <para>Select at least two workflow templates from the overview table.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>In the navigation bar of the web interface, click <inlinemediaobject><alt>Icon Edit</alt><imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/btn_edit.png" align="left" format="PNG"
                            scalefit="1"/>
                    </imageobject></inlinemediaobject> (Edit).</para>
                <result>
                    <para>The <guilabel>Edit</guilabel> dialog opens.</para>
                </result>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>Tick the checkbox next to each value you want to change for all selected workflow templates.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>In each of the selected fields, specify the desired new value for all selected workflow templates</para>
            </step>            
            <step>
                <stepalternatives>
                    <step>
                        <para>Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to save the changed settings for all selected workflow templates and close the dialog.</para>
                        <result>
                            <para>The changed settings for the selected workflow templates are displayed in the overview table and in the details pane.</para>
                        </result>
                    </step>
                    <step>
                        <para>Click <guibutton>Cancel</guibutton> to close the dialog without changing the settings.</para>
                    </step>
                </stepalternatives>
            </step>           
        </procedure>
    </sect1>
    <sect1 xml:id="delete_workflowTemplates">
        <title>Deleting Workflow Templates</title>
        <para>Use this action to delete a workflow template or multiple workflow templates. Proceed as follows to delete existing workflow templates:</para>
        <procedure>
            <step>
                <para>Switch to the <guilabel>Workflow Templates</guilabel> view.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>Select at least one workflow template from the overview table.</para>
            </step>
            <step>
                <para>In the navigation bar of the view, click <inlinemediaobject><alt>Button Delete</alt><imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="images/btn_delete.png" scalefit="1"/>
                        </imageobject></inlinemediaobject> (Delete).</para>
                <result>
                    <para>The confirmation dialog <guilabel>Delete Workflow Templates</guilabel> opens.</para>
                </result>
            </step>
            <step>
                <stepalternatives>
                    <step>
                        <para>In the confirmation dialog <guilabel>Delete Workflow Templates</guilabel>, click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to delete the selected workflow template (or workflow templates).</para>
                    </step>
                    <step>
                        <para>In the confirmation dialog <guilabel>Delete Workflow Templates</guilabel>, click <guibutton>Cancel</guibutton> to close the dialog <emphasis>without</emphasis> deleting the selected workflow template(s).</para>
                    </step>
                </stepalternatives>
                <result>
                    <para>If the workflow templates have been successfully deleted, a success message is displayed.</para>
                    <para>If the workflow templates could not be deleted, the corresponding error message is displayed.</para>
                </result>
            </step>
        </procedure>
    </sect1>
</chapter>